《盲点》前情回顾
Previously on "Blindspot..."
她不记得自己是谁
She can't remember who she is,
从哪里来  什么都不记得
where she came from, nothing...
新记忆开始于从时代广场上的包里爬出来
before she crawled out of that bag in Times Square.
通知联调局
-你认识她吗  -不认得
- Do you recognize her? - No.
那为什么你的名字会纹在她背上
Then why is your name tattooed on her back?
柯特·威勒
联调局
她所有的纹身都是新纹的
All of her tattoos, are brand-new.
-这是张寻宝图  -你说什么
- It's a treasure map. - Come again?
这是个地址  日期就是今天
It's an address and today's date.
郑超想炸毁自由女神像
Chao's gonna blow up the Statue of Liberty.
这是海豹突击队的纹身
It's a Navy SEAL tattoo.
如果她是突击队队员  肯定会在数据库里
If she was Navy, she'd be in our database.
要是她属于特种部队就不会
Not if she was special ops.
简  住手
Jane! Stop!
或许某些熟悉的事物
It's possible that something familiar
能唤起她的记忆
could trigger her memory.
这些感觉太不真实了
None of this feels real.
这女人到底是谁
Who is this woman?
她可能是我们拥有过的
She might be just the most important resource
最宝贵的资源
we've ever had.
感觉一切都脱离了掌握
Everything just feels so out of control.
我不记得自己是谁  过去的身份
I don't remember who I am, who I was.
无论我有过怎样的生活都化为乌有
Whatever life I had is gone...
破碎成无数零散的碎片
shattered into a million tiny pieces.
有时我感觉无法呼吸
Sometimes it's hard to breathe.
10小时前
我有个想法想尝试下
I have something I'd like to try.
这叫罗夏克测验
It's called a Rorschach test,
用于分析人们的性格特征
and it's designed to analyze personality characteristics
以及情感功能
and emotional functioning.
鉴于你处于失忆阶段
But with your amnesia,
我希望借助这些抽象的画面
my hope is that the ethereal nature
或许能激发你一些记忆
of the images might provoke another memory.
那么告诉我  你看到的是什么
So, tell me what you see when you look at these.
好的
Okay.
一张蜘蛛网  对吗
A spider web. Is that right?
答案不存在对错与否
There's no right or wrong.
我们再看下一幅  好吗
Let's try another one, shall we?
两枪脱靶
You missed two.
再来一次
Do it again.
是个枪靶
A target.
他们告诉过你  我可能是海豹突击队员吗
Have they told you they think I might be a Navy SEAL?
他们提过
They have, yes.
我只记得在树林里面训练
I only have one memory of training in the woods,
但感觉并不是很正式
but didn't seem very official.
海豹突击队的训练向来很非常规
SEAL training is very... unconventional.
所以倒是说得通
So, that actually makes sense.
我们再看下一幅  好吗
Let's try another one, shall we?
早上好  老姐
Morning, sis.
不好意思  我们把你吵醒了吗
Oh, damn it, did we wake you?
我约了位房产经纪明天见面
I got an apartment broker scheduled for tomorrow.
我们很快就不给你添麻烦了  我保证
We'll be out of your hair in no time, I promise.
不着急的  莎拉
There's no rush, Sarah.
这玩意儿是什么啊
Huh, what is that supposed to be?
那是煎饼好吧
It's a pancake, all right?
早上好  小家伙
Morning, little buddy.
说"早上好  柯特舅舅"
"Morning, Uncle Kurt."
-早上好  -早上好
- Morning. - Morning.
另外  爸爸昨晚来电话了
So, Dad called last night.
他想问问你
Just wanted to know
今年泰勒的祭日  你会不会回去
if you were gonna go back for Taylor's memorial this year.
不了  我工作太忙了
No, I've got too much going on at work.
他也不该去参加的
He shouldn't be going to that memorial either.
那会让别人不舒服
Makes people uncomfortable.
对  不过那是他们的事
Yeah, well, that's their problem.
你再考虑考虑  好吗
Look, just think about it, okay?
好
Yeah.
-再见  小家伙  -再见
- Bye, buddy. - Bye.
我们来这儿干什么
What are we doing in here?
你之前的记忆是在战斗中被唤起的
Your first memory was triggered by being active.
或许你的肌肉还记得什么
Maybe your muscles might remember something
只是大脑忘了
your mind can't.
这是M-4步枪
That's an M-4.
如果你想开枪
So, if you wanna fire that,
那么你就需要...
you're going to... need to do...
就是那样
Exactly that.
上吧
Step up.
好吧  试试看
Okay, let's try this.
她身上纹满了各种神秘的符号
Her body is covered in cryptic symbols,
地图碎片和谜语
map pieces, riddles.
无论是谁做的  此人必定有特别的用意
Whoever did this to her has a very specific goal in mind.
至于是何用意  现在还是个迷
And what that goal is remains a mystery.
我已经让最好的手下去分析了
I have my best people on it,
但这些信息过于多变繁琐
but this information is so varied and so dense,
可能要花上好几年来破译
it could take years to decode.
我注意到她脖子后方有一道伤疤
I noticed a scar on the back of her neck.
对  就是那个
Yeah, that.
能知道这是多久以前的伤疤吗
Got any idea how old that is?
这种东西很难判断
Well, it's hard to tell with these things,
但绝对不是最近的伤
but it's definitely not recent.
我不想伤到你
I don't wanna hurt you.
不会的  来吧  抬手
You won't. Come on, hands up.
来吧
Here we go.
出拳
Start swinging.
来啊  来啊
Come on, come on.
怎么样
All right?
再来
Again.
我们已经在简的身体上发现二十多种语言
We've captured hundreds of numeric sequences and phrases
写的上百条数字序列和词组
from Jane's body in over two dozen languages,
我们将其输入我所设计的数据库中
and we're feeding them into a database that I have designed
与我们有权限使用的所有数据库
that'll cross-reference them with every information system
进行交叉对比
that we have access to.
就像对她的纹身进行谷歌提醒
Like a Google alert for her tattoos.
比那要更加复杂一些
Well... it's a little bit more sophisticated than that.
不过没错  就像是谷歌提醒
But, uh, yes, it's-- it's like a Google alert.
怎么了  简
What is it, Jane?
你记起什么了吗
Did you remember something?
医院打电话过来  郑超死了
The hospital just called. Chao is dead.
姓名  郑超
郑超手术结束后
Chao had a massive stroke at around midnight
半夜就得了严重的中风
just as he was getting out of surgery.
不可能  他还那么年轻  很健康
I'm not buying it. He was young, healthy.
可他也中了一枪
He also got shot.
给我完整的尸检报告
Get me the full autopsy.
他是我找出幕后黑手的唯一线索
He was the only link we had to whoever did this to me.
线索还会有的
We'll find another one.
等等...看那里
Wait... look at that.
所有医生都在赶往郑超的病房
All the doctors rushing into Chao's room.
只有这个人往回走
and that one walking away.
搜查医院  找出这个医生
Canvas the hospital... find me that doctor.
我成功了
I did it!
什么  你找到他了吗
What, you found him?
我...什么  你说谁
I... what? Who?
不好意思  你们正忙着...
Sorry, you were in the middle of...
我又破解了一个纹身
Well, I unlocked another tattoo.
当我们正将这些数字纹身
So, as we scanned some of the numerical tattoos
扫描进数据库时
into the database,
有一个突然引起了我的注意
one of them just jumped out at me.
怎么样  看到了吗
Right? Do you see that?
好吧  不要把我们都当做是你
Okay, so, just pretend that we're not you.
好吧  简耳朵后面那个中文符号
Okay, the-- the Chinese symbols behind Jane's ear.
我们首先破译的线索是一个地址...
The first clue that we decoded was an address--
白街399号七号公寓
399 White Street, Apartment Seven.
所以呢
Okay?
看看这枚纹身
Okay, so, look at this tattoo.
开头是399  后面跟着一串字母
Starts with 399, has a bunch of letters
中间随便排序  末尾是7
just jumbled up in between, and then it ends with seven.
明白了吗
Do you see that?
这里有谁知道维吉尼亚密码
Who here knows what a Vigenere cipher is?
把手放下
Put your hand down.
这是一种多字母替换密码
It's a polyalphabetic substitution code.
没错  很棒
Yes, awesome.
维吉尼亚密码是一种根据密钥字母
A Vigenere cipher is a method of encrypting alphabetic text
对字母文本进行加密的办法
based on the letters of a key word.
除非你有密钥表
And unless you have the key word,
否则基本不可能破解
it is next to impossible to decode.
那么密钥是什么
So, what's the key word?
原纹身上两个数字之间的字符
The words between the two numbers on the original tattoo.
没错
Exactly.
利用"白街公寓"作为密钥
Use White Street Apartment as your key word,
那么它们之间无序的字母
and suddenly, the mess of letters in between
一下就成了"亚瑟·吉普森少校"
become "Major Arthur Gibson".
亚瑟·吉普森少校
所以第一条线索能用于解开第二条
So, the first clue unlocks the second.
很不可思议吧
Crazy, right?
这个吉普森是谁
Who is this Gibson guy?
根据他的服役记录
Okay, so, according to his service records,
吉普森曾驾驶F22在伊拉克和阿富汗执行任务
Gibson flew F-22 missions over Iraq and Afghanistan,
得到了一大堆奖章  包括银星奖章
earned a boatload of medals, including the Silver Star,
然后他受伤了  飞行生涯到此中断
and then an injury sidelined his flying career
他回到了美国
and he moved back stateside.
先在内华达州当了一个文员  后来在纽约
Took a desk job in Nevada before coming to work
为空军继续效力
for the Air Force in New York.
既然郑超死了  没法帮我
Now that Chao's dead and can't help me,
吉普森可能知道我是谁  是谁这么对我的
Gibson might know who I am, who did this to me.
我们得找他谈谈
We gotta go talk to him.
车管局有他布鲁克林的居住记录
DMV records have him living in Brooklyn.
-我们走  -我跟你们一起去
- Let's go. - I'm coming with you.
-好  你也去  -她也去吗
- Yes, you are. - She is?
你昨天还极力反对她参加行动
You were dead against her going into the field yesterday.
我错了
I was wrong.
我们还不知道纹身的作用
We don't know how the tattoos work yet.
她应该在现场
She should be there.
或许能唤起她的记忆
It might help her trigger her memory.
而且我们知道她能照顾好自己
And we all know she can handle herself.
让我去吧  我能帮得上忙
Please, I can help figure this out.
多谢  我们走
Thank you. Let's go.
吉普森少校  我们是联调局的
Major Gibson. It's the FBI.
谁派你们来的
Who sent you?
说来话长  能让我们进去吗
It's kind of long story. Mind if we come in?
我不知道他们跟你们怎么说的
Hey, I don't know what they told you,
但我没说
but I'm not talking.
我什么都没说
I haven't said a thing.
"他们"  "他们"是谁  你认识我吗
"They"? Who's "They"? Do you recognize me?
离我家远点
Get off my property.
看来他获得银星奖章靠的不是人格魅力
Well, he didn't get that Silver Star for his charm.
我们能弄到搜查令吗
Can we get a warrant?
不能
No.
纹身算不上正当理由
Tattoos aren't probable cause.
我能不能直接把门踹倒
Couldn't I just kick the door down?
看起来不是很结实
I mean, it didn't look that heavy.
不行  简  我们不能这么做
No, you can't, Jane. That's not how it works.
盲   点
第一季  第二集
房子暂时还不稳固 你们不能进去
Building's not structurally sound, I can't let you in.
-不会吧  -发生了什么
- Come on. - What happened?
整栋房子一下全炸掉了
The whole place was wired up to blow,
我还从没遇到过这种情况
I've never seen anything like it.
他还在家里就把自己的房子炸了吗  为什么
He blew up his own house while he was still in it? Why?
-我们要看看尸体  -没有尸体
- We need to see the body. - There isn't one.
什么意思
What do you mean?
爆炸的时候他就在里面
He was inside when it went up.
我也不知道该怎么解释
I don't know what to tell you,
我们到处都找过了
we searched the entire place.
声东击西
It was a distraction.
让我们专注于此  他得以金蝉脱壳
Keep us busy here while he got away.
不仅如此  还能毁掉他留下的所有证据
Not to mention, destroy any evidence he left behind.
什么证据
Evidence of what?
唯一幸免于难的是个老式的嵌墙保险柜
The only thing that survived that blast was an old wall safe.
我们得马上带它回实验室
We need to get that back to our lab immediately.
他为自己争取多少时间了
How much time did he buy himself?
我们一个多小时以前来的这里
We got here a little over an hour ago.
这家伙是谁
Who is this guy?
我与吉普森少校曾共事于阿富汗
I served with Major Gibson both in Afghanistan
并在纽约这里是他的指挥官
and as his commanding officer here in New York.
鲍尔斯
他是名出色的飞行员
He's a hell of a pilot.
他不是受伤了吗  改做了文职
I thought he was injured, moved to a desk.
一日是飞行员  终生是飞行员
Once a pilot, always a pilot.
那他到底发生了什么
So, what happened to him?
吉普森受到的是心理创伤
Gibson's injury was psychological.
他使一次任务损失惨重
He had a mission gone bad.
他造成了附带伤害
There was collateral damage.
死了多少平民
How many civilians died?
恐怕这是机密
I'm afraid that's classified.
就是说很多了
So, a lot then?
吉普森从那以后就变了
Gibson was never the same.
他的创伤后应激障碍愈演愈烈
His PTSD got worse and worse
最后我们只好把他召回
until eventually, we had to ground him.
他回国以后具体做什么
What exactly did he do when he got back stateside?
很抱歉  我无法透露更多
I'm sorry, but I can't say much more.
但是很不幸
But unfortunately,
即便是文职工作对他来说还是太辛苦
even the desk work got to be too much for him.
我们别无选择只能辞退他
We had no choice but to discharge him.
你们上次谈话是什么时候
When was the last time you spoke?
几个月前
A few months.
我们辞退他之后  他的婚姻也破裂了
After we let him go, his marriage ended.
他找不到工作
He couldn't hold down a job,
变得越来越偏执
he grew increasingly paranoid.
我想他一定很怪我
I think he blamed me.
他今早为什么要炸了自己的房子
So, why'd he blow up his own house this morning?
我也毫无头绪
I can't begin to imagine.
长官  我正在紧急排查
Look, ma'am, I'm racing to contain
潜在的爆炸因素
a potentially volatile situation,
我需要你如实相告
so I need to know what you know.
我能说的都说了
I've told you everything I can.
我也想尽我所能多为他做点什么
I wish we could have done more for him.
他是个好人
He was a good man.
这么说  吉普森是因为害死平民而自责吗
So, Gibson couldn't get over killing all those civilians?
那么一天  短短一瞬间
That one day, that-- that single moment
就成为了他余生的枷锁
defined the rest of his life.
有些事情能让人耿耿于怀
Some things are hard to forget.
博登说人的过去决定了现在
Borden says people are shaped by their past.
你觉得是这样吗
Do you think that's true?
我希望不是
I wish it wasn't.
万一我知道了自己的身份但不喜欢怎么办
What if I find out who I am and I don't like it?
帕特森的电话
It's Patterson.
我们开着扬声器
You're on speaker.
我在看吉普森的资料
I'm just going through Gibson's files,
有个地方不对劲
and something's not right.
鲍尔斯说他们辞退了吉普森
Powers said they sidelined Gibson
因为他有创伤后应激障碍
because he was suffering from PTSD.
但资料显示他反而被升职了
But according to his files, they promoted him.
离职了还是可以得到晋升的
They can still get promoted off the desk.
或许他们只是想照顾自己人
Maybe they're just trying to take care of their own.
或许吧  但他们还提升了他的权限
Maybe, but they also raised his security clearance,
从机密级升到了最高机密以上
from Secret to Top Secret and above.
如果吉普森真患有精神障碍
If Gibson was suffering from PTSD
他们不可能提升他的权限
they wouldn't have increased his access.
对  他们只会冻结他的权限
Nope, they would've frozen him out.
他曾是驻伊拉克和阿富汗的顶尖飞行员
He was one of their top pilots in Iraq and Afghanistan.
所以怎么着  他们将他送回内华达州
So, what, they move him back to Nevada?
给他升了职  还提升他权限
Bump him up in rank? Raise his clearance?
你怎么想
What are you thinking?
内华达州内利斯空军基地是
Nellis, Nevada is where
空军无人机计划的基地
the Air Force drone program is based.
他没有被辞退
He didn't wash out.
他们让他当无人机的操作员
They made him a drone pilot.
好吧  这样内华达的事说得通了
Okay, well, that explains Nevada.
但是他们把他调来纽约
But when they moved him to New York,
他的权限陡升
his clearance skyrocketed.
纽约可没有无人机计划
There's no drone program here.
只是我们不知道罢了
Not one we know about.
拜托  我工作要迟到了
Oh, come on. I'm gonna be late for work.
爸爸
Daddy?
吉普森  你在干什么
Gibson. What are you doing?
我需要你帮我点忙  亚历克斯
I need you to do something for me, Alex.
先把枪放下  好吗
Just put the gun down, okay?
我把一切都给了他们
I gave them everything.
我为他们做见不得人的勾当
I did unspeakable things for them.
吉普森  我女儿是无辜的
Gibson, my daughter is innocent.
我杀过很多无辜的人  亚历克斯
I killed a lot of innocent people, Alex.
-求你  放了她  -不
- Please, just let her go. - No.
这个国家背弃了我
This whole country abandoned me.
今天你要帮我给他们一个教训
And today, you're gonna help me teach them a lesson.
好吧  你听我说...
All right, listen to me...
不  你听我说
No, you listen to me!
照我说的做
You'll do as I say,
否则休想再见到你女儿
or you'll never see your daughter again.
美国空军基地
帮我打电话给将军
Call the general for me,
跟他说周四不行
tell him I can't make it Thursday.
鲍尔斯
Powers.
等等  什么
Wait, what?
不  那不可能  他们不...
No, that's not possible, they're not...
我们要动用一切资源
We gotta drill into this guy's life
调查这个人的生活
with everything we've got.
我要知道吉普森都跟谁联系
I wanna know who Gibson was talking to,
他的钱都花在哪里
what he's been spending his money on.
帕特森  我还希望你查查
And Patterson, I want you to find out about
他在自己家放的炸弹
the explosives he used on his own house.
没问题
Of course.
还有我要看看那个保险箱里有什么
And I wanna see inside that safe, okay?
里面肯定有什么重要的东西
There's gotta be something in there.
-这就去办  -谢谢
- On it. - Thank you.
他家  鲍尔斯
His house and Powers.
这只是个开始
This is just the beginning.
好吗  他是不会停手的
All right, the guy's not gonna stop.
我们得查出他下一个目标是谁
So, we need to find out who his next target is.
我不禁会想  是我们今天早上
I can't help but think we pushed Gibson
去敲他家门  才把他逼到这种境地的
over the edge this morning when we knocked on his door.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
这不是我们的错
That wasn't our fault.
我又没说是
I didn't say it was.
里德  够了
Reed, enough.
盲目被她的纹身诱导太轻率了
Blindly following her tattoos is reckless.
我觉得你还不明白她的重要性
I don't think you recognize just how important she is.
现在这么说还为时过早  你不觉得吗
It's a little early to make that call, don't you think?
不觉得  现在当务之急是找到吉普森
No. The most important thing is to find Gibson
并且阻止他
and to stop him.
你能跟帕特森一起去找找线索吗
So, can you join Patterson and find me a lead?
我们走吧
Let's go.
谢谢你
Thank you.
-万一他说对了呢  -不会的
- What if he's right? - He's not.
万一这些纹身就是陷井呢
And what if these tattoos are a trap?
-简  -我们根本不知道
- Jane. - We don't know anything
是谁对我做了这些  又是为什么
about who did this to me or why,
有人正在失去性命
and people are losing their lives.
简  这不是你的错  知道吗
Jane, this is not your fault, okay?
这不是你的错
This is not your fault.
威勒  跟我来
Weller, come with me.
是  长官
Yes, ma'am.
将军  这究竟是怎么回事
General, what the hell is going on?
今天早上一名退役空军飞行员
This morning a former Air Force pilot
炸掉了自己的房子
blew up his own house.
三小时后  他以前的指挥官
Three hours later, his former CO
死于空对地导弹袭击
dies in an air to ground missile attack.
拜托  请你告诉我
Please, do me the courtesy
这几起事件之间是有联系的
of admitting these incidents are connected.
它们是有联系
They are connected.
能详细说明吗
Care to elaborate?
美国决定采用本土无人机系统
It was decided the country  needed a domestic UAV program
不仅可以用于监视目标
that could not only surveil targets,
还能在极端情况下...
but also, in extreme circumstances...
采取行动
take action.
你是说  我们有武装无人机
You're telling me we have armed drones
正在美国上空盘旋着
flying over American soil.
以备不时之需
It's in place as a last resort.
我们从未对国内下达过发射指令
We've never dispensed ordinance domestically.
直到今天
Until today.
吉普森控制了一架无人机  他怎么做到的
Gibson got control of one of these UAVs, how?
他绑架了我们一位航空电子专家的女儿
He kidnapped the daughter of one of our avionics specialists,
逼他替换了控制卡  修改了无人机的程序
forced him to retrofit a drone with an alternate control card
其信号通过卫星传达
that severed its signal with our satellite,
让吉普森能进行远程操作
allowing Gibson to take over remotely.
现在那个女孩在哪儿
And where is that girl now?
我们相信还在吉普森手上
We believe Gibson still has her.
你们可以恢复控制或定位无人机吗
And the drone... can you recover control, locate it?
他把我们屏蔽了
He's frozen us out.
而且飞机的设计初衷就是能躲避雷达探测
And it was designed to evade radar detection.
它上面还有两枚导弹
It still has another two missiles,
我已经发动所有手下在想办法了
but I've got my entire team working on it.
我们要在他杀死更多人之前找到他
We need to find him before he kills anyone else.
一开始问你
You should've come clean with this
你就该说出实情了
as soon as we asked you about it...
我们不知道...
We had no idea...
不知道什么
No idea, what?
他会炸掉自己家吗
That he'd blow up his own house?
更严重的问题在于...
There were larger issues at...
比什么严重
Larger than what?
武装流氓无人机  十个死去的人吗
An armed rogue drone? Ten dead people?
还是被人从父亲身边夺走的小女孩
Or a little girl who was taken away from her father?
-威勒  -我们正在努力...
- Weller! - We are trying...
如果那个小女孩发生什么不测...
If anything happens to that little girl...
出去
Walk away.
他为什么这么做  将军
Why is he doing this, General?
他的动机可以帮我们预测下一个目标
His motives could help us anticipate his next target.
我也想知道
I wish I knew.
但我知道的是
What I do know is that Gibson
吉普森是美国空军训练过
is one of the most efficient killing machines
最高效的杀人机器
the Air Force has ever made.
你不觉得有些不对吗
Doesn't something feel off to you?
给简纹身的人知道无人机项目
Whoever did this to Jane knew about the drone program.
这个情报是绝密的
That information's above Top Secret.
她第一个纹身帮我们救了很多人
Her first tattoo helped us save lives.
希望这个也可以
Hopefully this one will too.
也许吧
Maybe.
也许我们是在捅马蜂窝
Or maybe we're about to knock over a hornets' nest.
我觉得吉普森并不认识我
I don't think Gibson recognized me.
郑超也不认识我
Chao didn't recognize me either.
目前为止  这些纹身给我们指的人
So, so far, these tattoos have sent us to people
好像跟我都没有任何关系
who don't seem to be connected to me at all.
如果他们和你没有任何关系
If they've got nothing to do with you,
那为何会纹在你身上
why are they on your body?
忏悔
Penance.
什么
What?
来看看这个
Hey, come take a look at this.
他在撒谎
He's lying.
我知道
I know.
但威胁一位三星上将起不到任何帮助
But threatening a three-star general does not help us.
对不起
Sorry.
你还好吧
How are you holding up?
我知道你不擅长应对孩子失踪这种事
I know you don't do too well with missing kids.
我没事
I'm fine.
柯特  我要知道你的心思在哪
Kurt, I need to know where your head is.
我一直在想泰勒
I've been thinking about Taylor.
那你或许应该找人谈谈...
Then maybe you should start talking to someone--
不  我不想谈
No, I don't wanna talk.
听我说
Listen to me.
她的失踪不是你的错
That girl's disappearance was not your fault.
当年你才十岁
You were ten years old.
我关于她最后的记忆...
One of my last memories of her...
是我们在后院爬树
we were climbing a tree in our backyard.
我们爬得很高
And we were up pretty high.
她一点也不害怕
She was fearless.
我在她上面
I was above her.
不小心踩到了她的手
I stepped on her hand accidentally.
她滑落了
She slipped.
她摔了下去  割伤了
She fell, cut herself.
在她后勃颈留下了一个大伤疤
It left a really big scar on the back of her neck.
简也有相同的疤痕
Jane has the same scar.
相同的眼睛
Same eyes.
她的年龄也相符
She's the right age.
我知道为什么是我了
I know why it's me.
我知道为什么我的名字纹在她背上了
I know why my name is on her back.
柯特·威勒
联调局
我觉得无名氏就是泰勒·肖
I think Jane Doe is Taylor Shaw.
你觉得简就是泰勒·肖吗
You think Jane is Taylor Shaw?
对
I do.
我不知道为什么  也不知道是谁
I don't know why and I don't know who.
但有人把她送回我身边
But someone sent her back to me.
这不可能
That's impossible.
为什么
Why?
为什么我的名字会在她背上
Why is my name on her back?
泰勒·肖都失踪25年了
Taylor Shaw has been missing for 25 years.
现在她回来了
And she's not missing anymore.
我们打开吉普森的保险箱了
Hey, we got into Gibson's safe.
里面是台气隙式电脑
It's an air-gapped computer.
抱歉  那是什么意思
Sorry, what does that mean?
是一台从未联过网的电脑
It's a computer that's never been connected to the Internet.
这样它就不可能
It makes it impossible
被第三方侵入或监控
for a third party to access or monitor it.
问题是  里面没什么东西
The thing is, there's not much on it
只有几个文档  这非常奇怪
but a few Word documents-- super weird.
但这个引起了我的注意
But this one caught my eye.
日期  时间  地点  总共五条
Dates, times, locations. Five of 'em.
它将五起看似毫无联系的爆炸事故联系了起来
They line up with five seemingly unrelated explosive accidents.
警察未找到
旅馆爆炸案嫌犯
三人在新布朗费尔斯爆炸案中丧生
两人在新墨西哥州高速路爆炸案中丧生
燃气故障  车祸...
Faulty gas lines, car crashes...
遇难者都是外国公民
Victims are all foreign nationals.
都来自中东  事故都发生于美国领土
All from the Middle East, all incidents occurring on U.S. soil.
无人机袭击
Drone attacks.
他们已经袭击过美国境内的目标了
They've already hit targets inside America.
这么说将军对我们撒谎了
So, the General lied to us.
每次事故旁边都有一组字母缩写
Each incident has a set of initials next to it.
有三个"AG"  代表亚瑟·吉普森
"AG", Arthur Gibson, for three of them,
还有两个"IM"
and "IM" for the other two.
我们查过了空军的服役记录
We searched the Air Force's employment records,
我们认为"IM"是另一位无人机操作员
and we think "IM" is another drone pilot--
伊万·马斯格雷夫少校
Major Ivan Musgrave.
有他的地址吗
Got an address for him?
当然
Of course.
开始行动
Let's move.
简  在这里等我们  好吗
Jane, just wait here for us, all right?
我们先去探探情况  好吗
Just until we get a read on the situation, okay?
谢谢
Thanks.
马斯格雷夫少校  我们是联调局的
Major Musgrave, this is the FBI.
马斯格雷夫少校
Major Musgrave?
伊万·马斯格雷夫
Ivan Musgrave?
威勒
Weller!
出口
你们干什么
What are you doing?
他们进去了吗
Did they go in there?
简  简  放开他
Jane! Jane! Let him go!
放开他
Let him go.
我们想审问他  不是杀了他
We want to question him, not kill him.
转过去  转过去
Turn over. Turn over!
我们要逮捕你
We're taking you in.
为什么  我没干什么坏事啊
Why? I didn't do anything wrong!
你没事吧
You okay?
好吧  好吧
All right, all right. Okay, all right.
-怎么  -好吧  我家里确实有一些
- What? - Fine, I got a couple of weapons
我不该有的武器
up there that maybe I shouldn't have,
但哪个空军士兵不是这样
but show me an airman who doesn't.
我们找你不是为这事
That's not what this is about.
你朋友吉普森碰上了大麻烦了
Your friend Gibson's in serious trouble.
我们要问你几个问题
So, we got some questions for you.
吉普森  他恨我
Gibson? Man, that guy hates me.
是我告发他的
I'm the one who turned him in.
-怎么  -他要告发整个...
- What? - Was about to blow the whistle on the whole...
不  你们没有权限知道这件事
No, you people don't have the clearance for this.
-继续说  -我要立刻见鲍尔斯上校
- Keep talking. - I wanna talk to Colonel Powers, now.
鲍尔斯死了
Powers is dead.
什么
What?
什么时候
Since when?
-威勒  -等一下
- Weller? - Wait a minute.
如果吉普森恨他的话...
If Gibson hates this guy...
而我们恰好把他带出来了...
We just brought him outside.
走  走  走
Go! Go! Go!
-快进去  -不  等下  不
- Get inside. - No, wait, no.
-进去  快进去  -不  等等  是他
- Inside, get inside. Get inside! - No, no, wait, that's him!
他就是在树林里的那个人  他就在那...
That's the man from the woods, he's standing right there...
放轻松  别动  别动
Easy, easy, easy, easy.
你可能伤到动脉了  好吗
Look, you might have hit an artery, okay?
如果拔出玻璃  你几分钟内就会失血过多
If you pull the glass, you could bleed out in minutes.
你还好吧
You all right?
希望你知道自己在干什么
I hope you know what you're doing.
我也想知道
Me too.
来吧  起来
Come on. Come on.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
他是怎么弄到这东西的
How did he get his hands on this?
他绑架了一位航空电子专家的女儿
He kidnapped the daughter of an avionics specialist
以此要挟帮他黑进无人机系统
who helped him hack the drone.
那女孩仍下落不明
That girl's still missing,
她需要我们的帮助
so she needs our help.
这太可怕了
This is terrible.
无人机项目不是用于不时之需  对吗
The program wasn't last resort, was it?
你们已经在实施了
You'd already been using it.
确认有五人死亡了
Five confirmed kills.
还有多少附带伤害
How much collateral damage?
无人机项目很肮脏
Drones are messy.
所以吉普森才想阻止此事吗
What, so Gibson wanted to stop it?
他是我们队伍中最优秀的飞行员之一
He was one of our best pilots, but even he
但即使是他  也无法接受平民死亡
couldn't stomach the loss of American civilians.
所以他原打算揭发此事吗
What, he was gonna blow the whistle?
是的  他还叫我帮忙
Yeah... yeah, he asked me to help.
但是  我出卖了他
But, um, I turned him in.
他们取消了他的权限  免去他的津贴
They stripped his clearance, they pulled his pension.
还威胁他的家人
Threatened his family.
是我们把他逼上绝路  毁了他的人生
We pushed him over the edge, we destroyed his life.
吉普森原本是个好人
So, Gibson was a good guy.
他只是想阻止杀戮
He just wanted the killing to stop.
可他今早杀了十个无辜的人
He killed ten innocent people this morning.
好人是不会这样做的
Good guys don't do that.
你认定好人就不会做坏事吗
You don't think good people ever do terrible things?
我认定坏人做坏事
I think terrible people do terrible things.
而好人会阻止他们
And the good people stop them.
吉普森暴走了
Gibson snapped.
他现在变得不可预测
He's unpredictable now.
他还剩一发导弹
He's still got a missile left.
谁会是他的下一个目标
Who's his next target?
我还指望你能告诉我呢
I was hoping you were gonna tell me that.
我不知道  那家伙有仇必报
I don't know, man, the guy's vindictive.
他会报复那些伤害过他的人
He's trying to hurt the people that hurt him.
鲍尔斯  还有我
Powers? Me?
那下一个是谁
Who is next on the list?
将军  飞行员在哪里操控无人机
General, where do the drone pilots operate from?
这是机密
That's classified.
吉普森要复仇  这是明摆着的事
Gibson wants revenge, that's obvious.
但他也对无人机项目怀恨已久
But he also hates the program and
并希望公诸于众
wants the public to know about it.
如果他想造成最大伤害  他会攻击哪里
So, where would he hit if he wants to do the most damage?
将军  拜托了
General, please.
-这里  -什么
- Here. - Excuse me?
这幢大楼顶层的三层楼
The top three floors of this building.
飞行员在那里操控无人机
The pilots operate from here.
但这说不通啊
But this doesn't make any sense.
如果他想炸掉我们这栋大楼
If he wanted to bomb our facility,
为什么到现在都还不动手
he would've done it by now.
他在等什么  为什么
Why wait? Why...
交接班
The shift change.
你们在说什么
Okay, what are you talking about?
无人机每次升空要飞好几天
The drones are in the air for days at a time,
但飞行员会每12小时换一次班
but the pilots fly them in 12-hour shifts
这样工作时间不会重叠
so there's no overlap.
一天两班  这里的每个飞行员轮流执勤
Twice a day, every pilot is in this building.
他在等换班的时机以便造成最大伤害
He's waiting for the overlap. Maximum impact.
致命一击可以使整栋大楼顷刻坍塌
A well-placed strike could bring this whole building down.
下一次换班是什么时候
When's the next shift change?
一小时后
An hour.
那我们现在就撤离人员
So, we're evacuating now.
要是他发现大楼里的人开始撤离
If he sees the building start to empty out,
他会立刻攻击  放手一搏
he'll hit us immediately, cut his losses.
我的手下认为他们马上就要
My people think they are very close
重新掌控那台无人机了
to regaining control of this drone.
光用脑袋想是无济于事的
"Think" isn't gonna cut it!
在吉普森杀死上万人之前
We have 60 minutes to find Gibson
我们只有一个小时找到他了
before he kills thousands of people.
我这就去
I'm on it.
我们正通过地下室的地铁连接处
We're funneling as many people as we can
尽可能多的疏散人群
through the basement subway connect, but there's no way
但要及时疏散整栋楼是不可能的
we're gonna evacuate the whole building in time.
告诉我你已经找到追踪这个人的方法了
Tell me you've figured out a way to track this guy.
若要随时盯着无人机
Well, he'd have to be somewhere pretty high up
他必须处在一个相当高的位置
to maintain line of sight with the drone.
好吧  所以我们能将他的位置
Okay, so, we've narrowed his location down
缩小到一处高地吗
to somewhere up high?
我已经获得无人机用来通讯的
Well, I've been given access to the exact frequency
精确频率
that the drone communicates on,
并追踪到信号的发射点在布鲁克林
and traced the signal's emanation point to Brooklyn.
-吉布森的老家  -那范围还是太大了
- Gibson's home turf. - That's a lot of ground to cover.
是的  但吉布森家里的爆炸物
Yes, but the explosives in Gibson's house
是一种十分特殊的爆破用炸药
were a very specific grade of demolition manufactured
仅用于加拉蒙建筑公司的工地
exclusively for Garamond Construction sites.
你们猜怎么着
And guess what?
吉布森在这家公司的两处工地工作过
Gibson worked for them at two sites--
都是高层建筑  都在布鲁克林
both new high rises, both in Brooklyn.
你和塔莎开一辆车
You and Tasha take the Lexus,
去一处建筑工地
hit one of the sites.
我和简去另一处
Me and Jane will split, cover the other one.
出发
Let's go.
今早我对你撒谎了
I lied to you this morning.
在射击场  我确实想起来一些事
At the shooting range, I did remember something.
太好了  是什么事
That's good. What was it?
一些不可原谅的事
Something unforgivable.
如果这之前我是个很坏的人怎么办
What if I was a terrible person before all of this?
我不觉得你是个坏人  简
I don't think you were, Jane.
无论你过去是什么样的  现在都不是了
Whoever you were then... that's not who you are now.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
你的第一本能是去救人  简
Your first instinct is to help people, Jane.
唐人街被打的妻子
Battered wife in Chinatown,
还有今天爆炸后你去帮里德
Reed after the explosion today.
你没有犹豫  而是直接去做
You don't hesitate, you act.
并且是在做正确的事
And you do the right thing.
我不知道你记起来什么
So, I don't know what it is you're remembering
或情景是什么
or what the context is.
但我认为你是一个好人
But I do think you're a good person.
我往楼顶去
I'm heading up to the roof.
好的  我留在这儿以防他逃跑
Okay, I'll stay here in case he doubles back.
用车里的无线电保持联系  好吗
Stay in contact with that radio in the car, all right?
如果你看到他  通知我
Let me know if you see him.
简
Jane!
简  这里是威勒  吉普森...
Jane, it's Weller. Gibson's...
威勒  你信号很差
Weller, you're breaking up.
简
Jane!
威勒  我听不到
Weller, I can't--
我听不到你说什么
I don't understand you.
简
Jane!
吉普森现在往你的方向去了
Gibson's coming down to you now!
我们会跟丢吉普森的  我去追他
We're gonna lose Gibson! I'm on him!
简  太危险了
Jane! It's too dangerous!
里德  萨帕塔
Reed, Zapata!
-简去追吉普森了  -她什么
- Jane's in pursuit of Gibson. - She's what?
我们分开了  她开着我的车
We got separated. All right, she's in my SUV.
锁定车上的GPS
So, lock onto that GPS
向她的位置汇合
and converge on that position.
知道她会开车吗
Do we even know if she can drive?
她会开车
Yes, she can drive!
忏悔
Penance?
简
Jane.
Jane...
你还好吗
You okay?
-你能动吗  -是的
- Can you move? - Yes.
我来把你弄出来
I'm gonna get you out of here.
过来
Come here.
女孩在哪儿
Where's the girl?
Where is the girl?!
艾米丽  艾米丽
Emily? Emily!
艾米丽
Emily, hi.
我叫柯特
My name's Kurt, all right?
我来带你回家
And I'm here to take you home.
好吗
Okay?
我们走
There we go.
艾米丽
Emily!
爸爸
Daddy!
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我们找到她了
We got her back.
是啊
Yeah.
我们找到她了
We did.
战鹰二号已经安全着陆
The Eagle Two has touched down safely.
空军已将这两起爆炸归为事故
Air Force is already spinning the two explosions as accidents,
引擎故障和天然气泄漏
faulty engine and a natural gas leak.
公众有权利知道真相
The public has a right to know the truth.
这不是我们说了算
That's not our call.
纹身方面还有什么发现吗
Any more hits on the tattoo database?
还没有
Not yet.
等等  我们不会真的
Wait a minute, we're not seriously
要一直这样下去吧
gonna keep doing this, are we?
今天我们刺激地一个人实施了暴行
We incited a man to rampage today.
怎么  你以为他造了个无人机控制卡
What, you think he built a drone control card
却不打算用吗
and didn't intend to use it?
他已经计划很久了
He'd been planning this.
没错  我们是逼得他把计划提前了
And yes, we forced him to up his timeline.
但要是真等到他准备好了再行动
But if he was able to wait until he was ready,
他们就阻止不了他了
there'd be no stopping him.
所以纹身是帮了大忙的
So, the tattoos helped.
那只是你的看法
That's one way of looking at it.
好了  今天就先这样吧
Okay, that's it for today.
威勒
Weller?
是  长官
Yes, ma'am?
如果你认为简就是泰勒·肖...
If you think Jane is Taylor Shaw...
-没错  -我需要确定
- I do. - I want to be certain.
我已经让人把肖的旧案件卷宗
I've already ordered Shaw's old case files
送去我们的实验室了
to be sent to our lab.
帕特森会对泰勒的DNA与简的进行比对
Patterson can test Taylor's DNA against Jane's.
会匹配的
It's gonna match.
这可说不准  她要真是泰勒
I don't know. If she is Taylor,
她这25年到哪去了
where has she been for 25 years?
她那些技能是从哪里学的
Where did she learn these skills?
还有为何有人要抹去她的记忆
And why did someone erase her memory
把她送回你身边
and send her back to you?
这说不通啊
It doesn't make sense.
就是她  我能感觉到
It's her. I can feel it.
你没事吧
Hey. You okay?
我忘不了吉普森的事
I can't stop thinking about Gibson.
他是做了很可怕的事  可他内心里
What he did was terrible, but some part of him
是想救人的
was just trying to help.
他让复仇蒙蔽了自己的思想
He let vengeance cloud his thinking.
想要揭露真相是一回事
It's one thing to want to blow the whistle.
杀人又是另一回事了
It's another thing to take lives.
谢谢你之前所说的...
Thank you for what you said earlier...
关于我的本能
about my instincts.
还有这一切
And for everything.
你身上的遭遇很可怕  简
What happened to you was horrible, Jane.
你一定会逢凶化吉的
Good can come of it.
我一直在想一个问题
I've been thinking about it.
我可能只是个信使
I might just be the messenger,
可你的名字却纹在我背上
but your name is still on my back.
他们本可以只纹"联调局"的
They could've just said "FBI."
为什么要送我来找你
Why would they send me to you?
我不知道
I don't know.
我把郑超的尸检报告拿回来了
We got Chao's autopsy results back.
我们发现他体内
We found elevated levels
氯化钾含量超标
of potassium chloride in his system.
什么意思
What does that mean?
他被下毒了
He was poisoned.
有人越过了层层障碍
Someone went through a lot of trouble
防止他向我们开口
to keep him from talking to us.
是那个医生  走开的那个
The doctor, the one that was walking away.
我们找了整家医院  没人能认出他
Canvassed the whole hospital, no one could place him.
天啊
Oh, my God.
目前还没证实
We have no proof yet.
我们打算对她的DNA进行检测
We're trying to verify it with some DNA
和泰勒旧卷宗上的比对
from Taylor's case files.
你知道这意味着什么  对吗
Well, you realize what this... this could mean, right?
爸爸一直被指控绑架了她
I mean, Dad's been accused of kidnapping her,
还将她杀害
of killing her.
虽然他们始终无法证实
It didn't matter they couldn't prove it,
可自从她失踪之后
he's had it hanging over his head
这事就一直困扰着他
since the day she disappeared.
妈妈也离开了他
Mom left him.
柯特  你25年来一直相信爸爸犯了谋杀罪
Kurt, you spent 25 years convinced dad committed a murder
可他从没做过
that never even happened.
如果那无名氏真是泰勒·肖
If Jane Doe is Taylor Shaw,
那爸爸就是无辜的
then dad is innocent.
-或许吧  -不  柯特  不是或许
- Maybe. - No, Kurt, not maybe!
你得去看看他
You have to go see him.
-莎拉  -他快不行了
- Sarah... - He's dying.
是肺癌  他的时间不多了
It's lung cancer, he doesn't have long.
求你了  去看看他吧
Please, just go see him.
趁还来得及  你们能和好如初
You can fix this before it's too late.
别  别出声
Don't... don't make a sound.